The risk to achieving of the inflation
target have increased. Risk to the labor
market have receded.
>> Make you wonder, Steve, what happened
between from the September meeting to
the from the meeting prior and I know
Jackson was in between because you know
they didn't hike and it wasn't that
different of a of a data set then.
>> No, they're wrong. They're wrong. Why
are the rates skyrocketing and the
expectations for red Fed rate hikes
skyrocketing? Why? CNBC misses the boat.
You literally just had Sarah go, "Well,
what changed between July and now? Why
all of a sudden are yield surging? Oh,
this is weird. The the microphone isn't
telling me." Okay, sorry. That's mean. I
just think it's so damn obvious and
nobody's paying attention to it. We pay
attention to it on this channel. He
brought it up many times before, BUT IT
PISSES ME OFF when the suits on CNBC
can't even figure it out CUZ IT'S NOT
THAT DAMN hard as to why all of a sudden
rate expectations are skyrocketing. It's
right here. It's the simplest freaking
chart you could look at. It's so damn
obvious and nobody pays attention to it.
It's the most blunt thing ever. the uh
Kevin Worsh's first meeting was over
here in June and during his first
meeting on a weekly basis, private jobs
were plummeting. We came off of this
surge right here which the PMIs and uh
you know the S&P flash indicators, the
ISM reads, they were telling us that
there was a massive surge in hiring in
right around here in March because of
the war. In other words, people are
like, "Well, we may as well manufacture
really quickly and get some
manufacturing cooking here because if we
don't, we're going to have these supply
chain issues because of hormuse and
fertilizer and uh what, you know,
helium, whatever. Maybe the Red Sea will
get slowed down." So, you get this boost
in manufacturing. When Kevin Worsh took
over, which uh Powell's last day in
office was uh well, as Fed chair, he's
still on the board of governors, was May
15th, right about here. We had a weekly
read of 30,500
jobs per week on ADP. And I like ADP
because it's private payrolls as opposed
to the uh BLS or the Bureau of Live
Statistics. Anyway,
Kevin Worsh took over here in
[clears throat] early June and that's
when he had his first actual meeting and
his first press conference. That's when
he's like, "Oh, we'll look at to the
left of the decimal for inflation." And
he wasn't in a rush to hike. Then in
July, and this is where Sarah Eisen, I
love Sarah, but come on. Sarah's like,
"Well, what changed?" Well, in the July
meeting, the ADP numbers were still
plummeting. And everybody's like, "Oh my
gosh, what if we go under zero?" And we
ended up getting a weekly read on July
25th of uh 8,250.
And a lot of people are like, "Oh, but
can what does the labor market even
matter?" It matters massively because
that's exactly why the Fed rapidly cut
with a 50 basis point cut before the
election in 2024, which of course a lot
of people thought was purely political,
but the labor market was falling off a
cliff at the same time you had the
Japanese carry trade issue and then it
rebounded. [laughter]
Uh, and so what changed? Well, look at
this. We bottomed out. And so we just
had our last Fed meeting uh you know
what about a week ago on September 16th
and you could see the beautiful rebound
that has occurred between those levels.
But we just got another ADP read
yesterday morning and it surged even
higher back to over 20,000 beating
expectations and you could see the total
Uturn in the trend. And so, duh, we're
seeing some aggressiveness in the rate
market right now, obviously. Let's go
look at that. But I'm also going to show
you this crazy, we're going to break
down, I'll summarize this crazy piece on
what's going on with the economy. This
just came out this morning as well, and
it's also driving yields up like crazy.
It's both of these things together that
matter, and you got to understand both
of them. So, first of all, if you zoom
into the bond market right now, the
10-year yield just skyrocketed. I mean,
we're up 7.5
bips. Bro, this sucks. Not only are we
up 7.5 bips on the 10-year, but you
literally just had bar from the Federal
Reserve come out and say, quote,
"Inflation is clearly not trending
towards target." Okay, well, that's
bearish. economic growth is strong and
the labor market is solid. It's not a
surprise that he's saying that right
after we ended up getting this read from
uh the uh the flash PMIs. You could
actually see these notes right here in
the meet Kevin app. So this this
portion's free uh for now at least. Uh
use it. May as well use it. Bar
inflation clearly not trending towards
target in a timely manner. Economic
growth is strong. Labor market is solid.
Fed was out of position. made an
adjustment in the right direction. Going
into recent policy meetings, the Fed
needed to recalibrate monetary policy.
Risks to achieving 2% inflation have
increased and the risk to the labor
market have receded. Further rate hikes
are likely needed. Great. So, this isn't
data dependent or data trend dependent
or whatever. This is crap, right? But
it's because the economy is in a weird
way booming. And I know that that
doesn't always sound relatable because a
lot of people are like, "How's the
economy booming? You know, it's so hard
to get a job." I'll talk about the labor
market uh in just a moment. But what
what I want to do right now is we're
going to pop on over to see what's going
on with yields. I will shout out uh
Koshi though. They are now a sponsor of
my startup called Reinvest. So that
means we get to reinvest more money into
real estate and uh the apps we're
developing. But shout out to them
because if you uh use this uh link
kalshy.comr/mevin
or just scan the QR code, you get 25
bucks when you sign up for Kelsey and
make your first trade. You can also use
coupon code meet Kevin when you sign up.
It's kind of cool. So big fan of this uh
and uh always gamble responsibly or bet
responsibly. But let's go look at KHI
and the KHI markets because yesterday I
said the odds of a rate cut at 5% on Khi
were ridiculously high. We made a whole
video on this yesterday, but they were
ridiculously high. They've now come down
to 4.5%.
This is a joke. They should, you know,
there's a spread in here obviously, but
this should be like zero. [laughter]
Okay, so there's not going to be a cut.
Like the fact that you could get a
payout betting that there will be two
cuts right now is is insane to me. The
economy would have to like war with Iran
uh honestly would have to be resolved.
War with Ukraine would have to be
resolved and the labor market would have
to fall off a cliff. It ain't going to
happen. The odds on the betting markets
now for a rate hike in the October
meeting uh are at 62%. That's up 10
basis points today on a trade level. You
can see that right here. Uh, now if I
pull up the CME watch group, I could see
CME has us for September of next year
starting to price in five to six
interest rate hikes. I kid you not, we
were at 3.5, call it over here, which is
off the chart. Okay, so we were at 3.5.
Where do we sit right now? Well, now the
middle of the bell curve is sitting at
four rate hikes. That's right here. This
is four rate hikes by September of next
year. This is five rate hikes. This is
six rate hikes. And what you could do is
you could add these up to get sort of a
cumulative percentage of us getting four
rate hikes. So four rate hikes we have,
let's add it up really quickly. We have
a 70,
we're pricing at a 76.7%
chance of four rate hikes. 76.7%
chance of four rate hikes. Uh we are
pricing in a 48% chance of five rate
hikes now. Literally a coin toss of five
rate hikes. Now before this flash PMI
data that just came out, which is really
important that we got to go through. I
want to be clear, I didn't think that we
were going to get four hikes. This data
here is starting to make me shake my
boots a little bit because my impression
has BEEN THERE'S NO WAY, NO WAY we are
getting four rate hikes. We're not
getting four rate hikes. There's no way.
It's not going to happen. Maybe we'll
get two. One in September, one in
December. That's it.
This Holy smokes, dude. This read is
absolutely nuts on on on what's going on
in the economy. So, this is the S&P
global read. It is a a business read on
what's actually going on at businesses.
It is a private survey. It is not based
on government data. If you go into the
GDP now data set, you can actually break
down what goes into it. And it is not
private data. This is public government
data. The government data is telling us
that we're sitting at 5.1% real GDP
estimates for right now, which is
remarkable. This is very, very high for
Q3.
Uh the private data just told us that we
should honestly shake our boots and
potentially expect more rate hikes. Why?
Because look at this. This is insane.
So, uh let's let's look at this from the
top. Oh yeah, sorry. I wrote all these
notes up here as well. For anybody who
invests in house hack, this isn't a
pitch or whatever, but I wrote this over
here. House hack which is obviously now
called reinvest. People wonder it's like
oh you know what what do you guys
reinvest? And so the idea is anybody who
buys which I'm not pitching here but
anybody who buys our courses our app or
the terminal that we have coming out
later this year which is going to be
sick. Uh or the rents that we get on
like $85 million of market value real
estate or now little sponsors that we
have like Kali which I actually think is
really cool. I think is win-win. Not you
know you get 25 bucks. I'm going to go
in there and I'm going to trade the Fed
too which I think will be really cool.
Uh but uh on top of that, you know, it's
more that House Hack can then reinvest.
So it's it's a cool partnership. But
anyway, um all of those things go into
us reinvesting in real estate. Uh and so
we're really excited about that. So the
more the economy booms, and that's why
we brought this up. The more the economy
does this, the better it is. So it's
like get out there. I sent a daily
wealth the other day. You if you
download the Meet Kevin app, you can get
the daily wealth on a daily basis, but a
daily wealth I sent out the other day
was like, "Go make hay, man. Like right
now there I I said I think there's no
chance in the next 6 months the economy
falls off a cliff. That means go make
money, baby. Make hay. And and I always
say put your money where your mouth is.
And it's like go make more money. The
more money you can make for your
business, for yourself, your startup,
your your education, whatever you could
do to go make more money, now is the
time to do it. As hard as it is, go make
more money. And I know that's easier
said than done. Sometimes it does mean
getting re-educated or reskilled in
something, right? Which sucks. But now
is the time to grind. Put the grind in.
But look at this. This literally
reiterates this. Business growth surges
to the fastest level in over 5 years and
job gains accelerate. This doesn't mean
you're late. You you could you could
still hop on on this boom. But look at
this.
Uh what you have right here is you've
got flash PMI expectations for services
were expected to come in at 55.3
and they came in uh not at 55.3. They
came in oh I can't put an arrow here.
There we go. They came in at 58.7 which
is a huge beat. Well above the 56.5
before it's a diffusion index so any
number above 50 is growth. We're
knocking on the door of 60 which is
insane.
uh flash US manufacturing
came in at 57 and the expectation was
53.7 which was actually lower than the
53 we had last time. But listen to the
commentary. Forget the numbers for a
moment. You could get lost in the
numbers. Listen to this over here. US
business continues to boom. If you
ignore the postcoid
lockdown, what do you have? The latest
improvement in business activity is the
greatest recorded improvement in
business activity going back all the way
to early 2015.
Business is clearly booming now in both
manufacturing and services and severe
supply chain bottlenecks are amplifying
the price pressures. So, how do you cool
demand? Okay, this is literally what
Barkin said yesterday. we covered this
um you know we also pinned it over here
if you go to the top of the meet Kevin
app sometimes I'll pin news that comes
through just to make it a little easier
to pay attention to it but one of the
things that he said yesterday which I
don't know if we as clearly talked about
it so I want to highlight it here but
one of the things a Barkin said
yesterday
was we need
to cool demand
when the federal Federal Reserve is
telling you they need to cool demand. It
means the economy is freaking booming.
It is on fire.
Obviously, that can lead to inflationary
pressures. Uh when supply is
constrained, right? So, if I remember
this correctly, um
I don't think I want to get into econ
101 right now, but the idea is when you
have supply and demand curves and the
economy moves, if the economy is going
to move and you get more, you know, you
got your P and Q, I'm going to do it.
When quantity demanded and quantity
supplied when they when both curves move
to the right because the economy is
going up and both curves move together,
price actually stays the same.
That's econ 101. Price stays the same.
So this is why people say you can have
economic growth without inflation. Yes,
textbook correct. The problem is right
here, supply chain bottlenecks. When you
have bottlenecks, then what you have in
econ 101 is the quantity demanded
exceeds the quantity that is capable of
being supplied. That's when you get
shortages for memory [clears throat] or
for chips for components and
manufacturing. They could be
motherboards. They could be field
programmable gate arrays. They could be
uh A6. It doesn't matter the AI capex
boom, the consumer boom on services that
we're seeing, not everybody's I, you
know, I want to be clear, okay? Not
everybody's printing money. In fact, if
you go over here to a wage study, uh,
wage suppression, in other words,
people's like the worker share of
corporate income has been plummeting.
So, not all workers are winning here. I
want to be sensitive to that. So, you
know, like when I talk about the economy
and I'm like, "Wow, everything's
booming." I also understand that what's
booming is corporate profits. The
companies are making more money. Workers
as a share of those profits have not
been booming. So, this is where it's
like, how can you get exposed to assets,
right? How could you get exposed to real
estate? How could you get exposed to uh
equity in either the company you have,
whether through stock options or direct
stock purchase or or whatever, right?
That's how you end up participating in
that boom. Easier said than done, right?
So, [clears throat] I want to be mindful
of that. It is corporations that are
winning and AI is just going to make
that worse. So, anyway, so you got these
supply chain bottlenecks, which this
basically reads like a giant middle
finger to the Federal Reserve. They're
basically saying, "You guys are way
behind on rate hikes." Listen to some of
these notes, okay? US business activity
growth accelerated for a fourth
successive month in September to reach
the fastest rate in over 5 years.
Renewed improvement in manufacturing
output growth. Employment also rose
sharply with jobs added at a pace not
seen in over four years. Just pause on
that for a moment. We are now getting
flash indicators that the economy is
adding jobs at a pace we have not seen
in 4 years. you are screaming a freaking
middle finger to the Federal Reserve to
hurry up
and and hike. And I just I mean I' I've
been talking about this segment so much
here. I just realized the cues have also
fallen off a cliff. Uh and
people are going to think I am so full
of freaking crap, but course members
know. Dude, I was bearish this morning.
I said, "Look,
between now and Friday, especially with
no deal,
you're probably going to have a buy the
dip opportunity." Uh, and I targeted
sort of a strategy for two days for
buying the dip. Uh, and uh, and I'm
like, you know, hitting alltime highs on
the NASDAQ 100 is cool and all. We hit
that earlier than expected, but but
like, let's take a little chill pill
here until we get a deal with Iran,
okay? So, be extra cautious. That was
our alpha report this morning. AND DAMN,
THAT PUPPY COOKED. UM,
but I, in fairness, I also was not
expecting this. This report was crazy.
Uh, employment uh, okay, backlogs for
work continued to rise at an increased
rate and supply chain delays
intensified, aka more rate hikes.
Uh, and this fight for corporate
profits, by the way, just leads to more
advertising spend as well,
which I think overall ends up being good
for the advertising companies, Meta
included. They've got an event today and
tomorrow. We'll cover that later though.
Registering. Okay, here we go. Uh,
output index registered the fastest
expansion since July 21 and an
acceleration of growth for the fourth
consecutive month. So in other words,
the rate at which we're growing is the
fastest that we've seen since July of
21.
And uh we are now four months in a row
of growth. So that takes us back to
about the end of May. The steepest rise
in output we've now seen in over 5
years, which is a welcome development
because it was accompanied not just by
services sector. That was the steepest
rise in output in 5 years. But
manufacturing also grew to the fastest
level since April of 22, which basically
means both manufacturing and services
are booming. I drew these red lines
here, so forgive me for marking up their
graph, but I think it shows you a very
clear uptrend in the economy. The
economy is still booming. Now, do we
need to be concerned about recessionary
risk? Of course,
the labor market is one of the canaries
in the coal mine. And then the labor
market is saying you bro this canary is
singing. This canary is having baby
canaries. This canary is on fire.
You go over here. This was barking
yesterday. This period will be more like
the mid1990 cycle adjustment. I don't
know.
But this could end up being a very
accurate forecast that maybe, just
maybe, 2026 is actually kind of like
1995 and not like 1999.
And anybody who knows about the dot
bubble peaking in May of uh what was it
between March and May of 2000
doesn't want to hear any reference to
1999. Yeah, [laughter] you start making
references to 1999, it's just getting a
little bearish. So, ironically, the
stocks are going down right now because
the economy is booming so much and you
have to price in more rate hikes.
Let's take a look at this. Uh, you had
for employment, this is very bullish.
What do we have for employment here?
Companies backlogs of uncompleted
orders, a key indicator of capacity
utilization and future business growth
rose in September at the fastest pace
since May of 22, having accumulated at
an increased rate in both manufacturing
and services. The rise in backlogs of uh
work encouraged for firms to take on
more staff. Uh yeah, like we just hired
three more people at reinvest, you know,
house hack. We think we're booming and I
I mean I'm also I feel like putting in
so much more work uh because it's so fun
right now with just like all the
different verticals that we have cooking
and growing. So it's really fun as as as
a startup. But like again I say I'm a
big fan of put your money where your
mouth is but also put your actions where
your mouth is. So, it's sort of like,
you know, I don't just I'm not just the
person that's gonna, you know, sit and
have a eye tie and then daily wealth
send people a notification and go, "Hey,
make sure you go grind out there." It's
like, "Nah, man. Your boy me Kevin
grinding as well." And I think that's
obvious. You know, you could see that.
I'm trying to pull up the um world
interest rate probability sheet in the
meantime. Uh we we'll look at that in
just a moment, too. So, take a look at
this. Prices price pressures have
intensified in September. This is
another middle finger of the Fed.
average input cost measured across both
goods and services surged higher. The
overall rate of inflation has now hit
its highest level since October of 22.
So this is not a Fed number. This is not
CPI. This is not uh whatever blah blah
blah. What this is is money honey in the
private sector going damn we got pricing
power right now. That's what Barkin said
yesterday as well that he wasn't sure
that company's pricing power was
actually declining which implies that
you know people can keep raising prices.
So you know something to be aware of.
Now if you look at at the world interest
rate probabilities I am now looking at
uh a peak of 3.66
additional rate hikes by September 15th
which is really interesting because if
you include the September hike that now
pushes us up to 4.66 66 hikes priced in
fully priced in you have fully priced in
4.66 hikes between now and September
15th of next year which means we are
trending towards almost pricing in a
full fifth rate hike. Okay. So then what
we have over here wage pressures were uh
also noted to have picked up in many
cases. Not great. Inflation was blamed
on higher fuel and transport costs,
though again wage pressures also noted
to have picked up. Supply shortages are
an issue. Job growth hit the highest
level since February of 21. And that's
the report. So, you have a lot of data
here, whether it is the uh Atlanta Fed
data, this data that just came out from
the S&P flash PMI, which is the first
read of September,
and the ADP tracker clarifying why, you
know, people are confused about why is
the Fed hiking, why are yields higher?
This is it. This is the explanation. Uh
and so I think you know when you pay
attention to this there are
arbitrageages you could take advantage
of in the betting market whether it's
Kalshi or whatever but it's also
important for
when you're investing in stocks to be
aware of the headwinds that you're
facing because these yields are now very
rich. We've now clearly broken through
5%. We are now up 8.9
basis points. And what I'd like you to
see is this the yield curve. The yield
curve is legit flat. It has moved zero.
Which basically means if there's no
change between the 2-year and the
10-year, it means both the 2-year and
the 10-year are going up at the same
rate. And they're basically giving you a
double middle middle finger. It's sort
of like the 10 year is like and the
two-year is like
and and they're both GOING WE'RE BOTH
GOING UP AND and the difference between
the two is staying constant. Uh that's a
sign of an economy that's
hot. Unfortunately, that is going to
weigh on rate hikes. And the fact that
we don't have an Iran deal yet, you
know, we still got time. The UN General
Assembly ends Monday.
Uh the fact that we don't have a deal
yet is making people nervous. So, some
work to do on Iran while at the same
time you've got
a booming economy. If you like that
video, check this one out. I think
you're going to love it.
>> Why not advertise these things that you
told us here? I feel like nobody else
knows about this.
>> We'll we'll try a little advertising and
see how it goes.
>> Congratulations, man. You have done so
much. People love you. People look up to
you.
>> Kevin Papra there, financial analyst and
YouTuber. Meet Kevin. Always great to
get your take.